# **LUKE SHAFER**

# **FULL-STACK WEB DEVELOPER**

## CONTACT

614 - 585 - 3382 hello@lukeshafer.com Columbus, Ohio

### Links

<u>lukeshafer.com</u> <u>github.com/lukeshafer</u>

# **SKILLS**

# Languages

- TypeScript JavaScript
- CSS & preprocessors
- Python
- HTML

# Libraries & Frameworks

- React
- WordPress
- Svelte/SvelteKit
- Strapi
- Astro

## **Practices**

- Accessibility
- Semantic HTML
- Componentization
- Scalable Design

#### **Soft Skills**

- Project management
- Team communication
- Customer service
- Patience
- Adaptability

# **PROFILE**

Hi! I'm a web developer with over 5 years of professional experience, focused on accessible, modern, and concise design. I'm experienced in modern frontend web technologies, including React and Svelte, and can quickly learn any stack or technology introduced to me.

## **EXPERIENCE**

## **Freelance Web Developer**

Columbus, Ohio | Mar 2022 - Present

I started Luke Shafer Web Design to help local small businesses with their web development needs. I use modern frameworks like SvelteKit and Astro to build custom, flexible, and accessible sites for my clients.

## Implementation Specialist, TrueCommerce

Columbus, OH | *Jan 2021 - Aug 2022* 

Designed EDI software integrations using scripting in accordance with customer business requirements, and provided personable customer service.

# Online Coding Instructor, CodeWizardsHQ

Remote | Sept 2020 - Feb 2021

Led curriculum-based courses with students in grades 3-12, teaching coding concepts from scratch. I taught classes in Python, Javascript, and Scratch.

### **PROJECTS**

#### Fridge Magnets

fridge.lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/fridgemagnets

Online multiplayer word game; an implementation of the card game <u>Ransom Notes</u>. Built with <u>colyseus.io</u> for the game server, and SvelteKit for the frontend game UI, using TypeScript to power the full stack.

### **Personal Portfolio**

lukeshafer.com | github.com/lukeshafer/lukeshafer.com

My personal portfolio and a place for prospective clients or employers to view my work. Statically generated in SvelteKit and hosted on CloudFlare Pages.

### **EDUCATION**

### **Bachelor's, Computer Science, 2019**

University of Cincinnati, Cincinnati, Ohio

